- Did you have control?
Are you sure you were in control?
- I am fixing firewood.
You can bring wood home with you if you want.
This is more worth more than gold nowadays.
- Scream ... oh.
- My trip into the prepping, it was that I lived into town and longed for the country.
- Yes.
-And I started to listen to a podcast with an old man in Texas who is preparing.
Now he has become a little sick in his head I think, so I stopped listening to him.
So he has been radicalized, I think.
- But that is a trip you are also out on.
It is not me who has become strange, it is society that has become strange.
- Can you go with?
- Yes, come, come!
- Surely it is wonderful?
- Like hell!
Here you have celebrity Sweden's biggest prepper, Kalle Zackari Wahlström, who will help us understand the phenomenon a little better.
- What is a prepper?
- One prepper is that you are interested in preparing for different eventualities.
- What are they afraid of?
- You can imagine a more dangerous pandemic.
And then war feels like a scary thing going on in the world.
- Have I?
By not being prepared?
- Shit in it.
Should we go and look at the hens?
- Okay
- Ah came
- So there are quite a few pancakes that you can fry by these
- You just go.
You have such a natural pondus.
Now talk to them.
You are like your own being.
As one cannot control and control.
What do you have in here?
- Here I have meat.
- Oh damn what a lot of meat you have.
I think this thing with prepping is like this ...
It gets so big.
It can also just be like this.
That I have some flour.
There are just a few extra weekly documents.
So do you have it at home late
- I think you're cruel.
- You have no small children.
You live alone.
You have a pretty bold salary.
You have the way to control your preparedness.
So you haven't done it in just ... it's laziness.
I think it's so damn tragic just.
I think it's tragic.
Hahahaha
- What is the fucking tone?
- Here I have made snus.
That is why it looks like this.
- Wait so ... in a possible crisis you wouldn't even have to buy snuff.
- It's such a speed on you.
- How do I go?
Shows here how I go.
- So you go.
So it's yours ... it's your walking style.
- Yes.
Here you can see my secret prepping weapon.
- huh?
- 2.5 tonnes of wheat.
That's what I can do for quite some time.
- How 2.5 tons of wheat?
- Yes.
I think so
- There are absolutely crazy preppers.
- Do you have weapons?
- Yes I have.
- And then you are not shy to use in a crisis if someone comes here?
- Well, I would be, I would be very shy to shoot someone, I think.
I would think about once and twice before I actually killed someone with my rifle.
- But then you shoot.
- So, three quick thoughts.
Then it slams.
- Where do you think we will end up on this trip as we get deeper into the core of the prepping?
- You will surely think people exaggerate.
Instead, try to have an open sin and think like this, they do what takes responsibility for themselves and their family.
If something happens, then the preppers will be kings.
So tighten you, now it gets off.
- Yes.
- Hello?
- Hello!
- Mauri
- Reidar
- I immediately note TV and video surveillance.
- Yes, it started with it being for the prepping.
Plus I have had some worries with Practical Jokes.
- Okay.
- Among other things, a friend here who came here and put where you have your car.
A stone of 2 tons.
- But what kind of friend?
- I wonder that too.
- Would you be able to walk around and have a look at all the prepping details?
- I have stuffed a bit like this.
It is not really legal to hold.
So to speak.
- So we can't see it then?
No, but there is something else.
Here I have picked up some stuff from a prepping place we have.
- A bear trap?
- We'll see if we can rig one here.
- Yes, just gently.
- Good to have.
- I think the state has more secrets than we would like to know.
Hi Ludvig
- I won he at a competition on Facebook.
- He doesn't bite, right?
- ehhhhh ... both yes and no.
- Both yes and no?
- But you are a man with many surprises Reidar.
It feels like you have at least one more messy thing.
- Yes, it would be the home building over there.
- This is your Bug Out Vehicle.
So what you use if you have to escape in a crisis situation.
- Exactly.
Each group will have one to two vehicles each.
We will have about food for 9-12 months with us.
I try to keep him in control anyway.
- You try?
-I try to.
- How much are you talking about this with your wife?
- It is as soon as possible.
I think she is getting tired of me now.
- The first time you Reidar met, how fast did it take before he started talking about prepping?
- We sat non stop and talked for two to three hours.
-If?
- If prepping.
- Oh!
Have you told me everything you have for me?
- Some things are safest not to know.
But where are they unknown, hidden things?
They are scattered each and all around the country.
Huh?
You have as a group of prepper for which you are partly the leader.
- Yes.
Then we take coffee for so long.
- Can you tell the camera how much coffee you drink every day?
- Three to four such a day.
- It's too much, Reidar.
- No, I'm just feeling it.
Then the guests began to roll in from different parts of Småland.
An incredibly diverse crowd of people who all snow in on Prepping.
- Yes, welcome then.
We have received some complications.
Route 2 is gone.
I have found a suitable place there.
- Yes, up there yes.
- What will you do in this place?
- There we gather all vehicles, all our preppersaker and camp.
These crosses.
These are places that we know there are military barracks.
- Is this all military bases?
- As we have found so far.
- What's that?
- This is a regular inventory list now when we order.
- The dream right now is to rebuild the store.
- Oh yes, that's it.
Because it is as they say, if you are at the bottom, there is only one way.
And that's up.
- But I think we can cook a lunch then, as you usually cook it?
- White prayers and old honest goulash soup.
- Now Reidar has not talked about prepping in three seconds.
- It's a record!
- New record.
- Is it a new record?
- Almost.
- An applause to Reidar.
Three seconds.
- Then I get more time to think.
- On what?
- Prepping.
It's not so bad food to live on.
- I thought this was delicious.
- Everything you can eat, only they are the right spices or some good accessories.
- Yes, is the situation as it is so.
Because Nina and Reidar's situration look like it does-
- I felt there was one last thing I wanted to do.
- Due to the economy and your prepper store-
So I thought I would invite you to a surprise.
... Martin Svennberg!
- Can we release now?
- Yes absolutely.
What are you looking for?
- In a shorter but intense crisis, it is most important to have water and heat.
You have a little plaid.
- But this is.
Plus points?
- Yes, not many, but a bit anyway.
- Here I have sunscreen.
I have a lot of that.
There I am well -spread.
- Yes but that's good
- Number two.
- Gaspis.
- To boil water is the easiest way to clean water.
- But this one can also have to heat food.
For example, if you want to heat your tuna.
- What is the scornful tone?
- Number one.
Just dealing with water exclusively.
For three days without water, do we manage?
- Not on...?
- Not on.
Hello.
Return up to the trip to Norrland and our last visit.
His name is Andreas and is Sweden's biggest name in prepping.
- When it comes to the modern Swedish balanced prepping, you could call him the Urap.
For several years he blogged under the name Urvaken and even appeared in the media.
But a year and a half ago, he suddenly put the blog down and disappeared completely from social media.
- Andreas went from being the wound to just disappearing all of a sudden.
- He may have gone completely off-grid.
What happened was that Andreas moved out permanently to his evacuation home.
Since then not a squat.
And no thanks to all kinds of media.
- I tried to do TV shows about prepping.
I tried to contact mass preppers, including then the ancestry
Could not get hold of him.
So you have managed to fix it, it is damn powerful then.
Hour after hour by car towards deepest Norrland with a promise not to state his coordinates in the program.
- Type here, like all civilization, ends.
Deep in that forest he lives completely alone.
It is completely impossible to get here by car.
You have to walk the last kilometers as well.
Listen how quiet it is.
Absolutely silent.
- Hello!
Hey!
- Mauri!
- Andreas!
It feels like you have made prepping a lifestyle in a way that not everyone has done.
- Yes, that's how I have chosen to live my life.
- Should we have a little look at how you live here?
- Can we do.
- What is this?
It's a simple greenhouse to extend the season so I grow in these.
- If you open, you will see.
- What is this?
- It's rice, macaroni, salt and sugar.
It's all possible there.
- No!
- I'm pretty introverted really.
That is what people have very difficult.
My mother is very difficult to compare that I live here myself.
How can you live like that?
Aren't you alone?
Although I don't think so.
- How many years would you survive on all the food you have out here?
- It was boring news to me.
But you see all the small prepper details everywhere.
- Yes, there is food everywhere.
- And what's in here?
- Here is the toilet.
And since there is no drain and no water, it will be toilet afterwards.
- It doesn't smell midsummer in here.
- Don't it?
- No.
- I sacrifice a lot of things by choosing to live like this.
I could almost say that I could be prepared to kill for a hot shower sometimes.
- And there is just one machete type.
Should I be scared?
- No.
If you are not going to be invited like that.
- But I'm invited here.
- We have discussed this so many times you and I now.
It is like a private party where the word private is very with big letters so.
- Yes, private.
Not everyone can come.
- I may have to be clearer with my no.
- Yes, may I come?
- No.
- Yes, it's ... because now you flash, I think.
- 0.10 Millisievert?
Who the hell is Siewert?
Wondering then?
- Yes, he is, Siewert Öholm.
- What can you really joke about?
- But Siewert Öholm is dead.
Are we looking for Siewert Öholm's spirit then?
- If you hear someone who starts whispering video violence and such things, then ...
- It's 0.10 of him here.
* whispers* violent society.
* whispers* 19-year-old Satanist
Siewert ...?
- It's too little Siewert for him to answer.
- How much are all these silver coins worth you think?
- So a silver coin I would say is worth about SEK 300.
So you keep it in a thousand or so there.
- But wait then your silver coins are worth SEK 100,000, which is here.
Oh God.
You can't avoid having weapons here too.
- Yep.
- Look at yourself.
You are ready.
- I've been working on this for 15 years.
It's just accelerating.
- Yes.
Against here.
- Yes ..
No!
- It is a secret world in many ways prepping.
Have you told us everything, everything you have?
- No.
- huh?
But you have kind of hiding places.
- Then I choose not to answer.
- God, it's like a politician there, it's a little exciting.
This was probably a little wrong.
- The world's strongest pizza.
- Mauri, wrong channel.
This is food coma away.
- Yes, then we were back on
Youtube channel.
A new day has Grytt in Norrland
- And I felt yesterday there was like a question that hung a little in the air.
Now I'll go and ask that question one last time.
- But we have discussed that, no!
- A hug?
- You can get that.